# Sammy Robinson Full Stack Developer

Prockton, MA 02301-3253 🛗 27 Mar 1990 🖂 sammy.robinson327@gmail.com

**15127824477** 

# **PROFILE**

I bring over ten years of experience as a full-stack engineer in web and mobile app development. My proficiency spans the entire development cycle, with a specific focus on front-end development using modern JavaScript libraries and frameworks. I'm recognized as an expert in JavaScript and Shopify. My passion for continuous learning, adaptability as a team player, and innovative problem-solving skills drive my work.

# **SKILLS**

#### **Frontend**

Vue, Angular, React, JavaScript/TypeScript, Tailwind

## **Content Management System**

Shopify, Hydrogen, Polaris, Liquid

#### **Database Management Systems**

MongoDB, MySQL, Redis

#### **Backend**

Node.js, Express, PHP, Laravel, GraphQL

#### **Version Control Tools**

Git(Github, Gitlab), SVN

#### **DevOps**

AWS(Lambda, API Gateway, Elasticsearch, S3, EC2), Firebase, Docker, Kubernetes, Testing tools (Cypress, Mocha, Jest, Enzyme)

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

PieSoft, Senior Full Stack Engineer

Aug 2021 – Aug 2023 Bethlehem, United States

- I contributed to a marketing platform project, employing a technology stack that included React, Vue, Next.js, Nuxt.js, Node, Java, Spring, and Laravel.
- I successfully set up AWS API Gateway to host the Laravel API using AWS Lambda functions.
- Additionally, I created Elasticsearch queries to ensure fast and precise search functionality and designed scalable RDS instances for relational databases.
- I also played a role in mentoring junior developers.

### sophilabs, Full Stack Engineer

Jul 2018 – Jul 2021 NYC, United States

- Developed and customized e-commerce websites using technologies like React, Shopify, Hydrogen, Polaris, Liquid, GTM, Google Analytics 4.0, Google Ads, MySQL, and Google Map API.
- I have expertise in crafting visually appealing and interactive Shopify stores using modern JavaScript frameworks and Shopify's design systems.
- I've optimized performance with serverside rendering, seamlessly integrated the Polaris design system, and customized themes with React and Vue.js while leveraging Shopify's Hydrogen framework and Liquid templating language

### mark2market, Software Developer

Apr 2013 — Jun 2017 Sao Paulo, Brazil

 Built website using Laravel, utilizing MySQL for the database, and a RESTful API for the backend.

Freelancer, Software Developer

Oct 2011 - Apr 2013

# **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Computer Science,** Federal Technological University of Paraná Apr 2007 – Sep 2011 Rebouças, Curitiba, Brazil